<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAACArtsVA" Name="ACPSA value added by ACPSA industry" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>1</Code><Description>Total value added</Description><Definition>Gross domestic product (GDP) by state is the measure of the market value of all final goods and services produced within a state in a particular period of time. In concept, an industry's GDP by state, referred to as its "value added", is equivalent to its gross output (sales or receipts and other operating income, commodity taxes, and inventory change) minus its intermediate inputs (consumption of goods and services purchased from other U.S. industries or imported). GDP by state is the state counterpart of the Nation's GDP, the Bureau's featured and most comprehensive measure of U.S. economic activity. GDP by state differs from national GDP for the following reasons: GDP by state excludes and national GDP includes the compensation of federal civilian and military personnel stationed abroad and government consumption of fixed capital for military structures located abroad and for military equipment, except office equipment; and GDP by state and GDP have different revision schedules.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Total ACPSA value added</Description><Definition>ACPSA Value added consists of the gross output of an industry less its intermediate inputs; the contribution of an industry to the gross domestic product (GDP).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>100</Code><Description>Core arts and cultural production</Description><Definition>Core ACPSA industries are originators of ideas and content that are associated with the creation of arts and culture.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>111</Code><Description>Performing arts companies</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises (1) companies, groups, or theaters primarily engaged in producing the following live theatrical presentations: musicals; operas; plays; and comedy, improvisational, mime, puppet shows, and dance; (2) establishments, commonly known as dinner theaters, engaged in producing live theatrical productions and in providing food and beverages for consumption on the premises, and (3) groups primarily engaged in producing live musical entertainment. Theater and dance groups or companies may or may not operate their own theater or other facility for staging their shows. Musical groups and artists may perform in front of a live audience, or in a studio, and may or may not operate their own facilities for staging their shows.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>112</Code><Description>Promoters of performing arts and similar events</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in (1) organizing, promoting, and/or managing live performing arts productions, sports events, and similar events, such as state fairs, county fairs, agricultural fairs, concerts, and festivals, held in facilities that they manage and operate and/or (2) managing and providing the staff to operate arenas, stadiums, theaters, or other related facilities for rent to other promoters. Theatrical (except motion picture) booking agencies are included in this industry.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>113</Code><Description>Agents/managers for artists</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments of agents and managers primarily engaged in representing and/or managing creative and performing artists, sports figures, entertainers, and other public figures. The representation and management includes activities, such as representing clients in contract negotiations; managing or organizing clients' financial affairs; and generally promoting the careers of their clients.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>114</Code><Description>Independent artists, writers, and performers</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises independent (i.e., freelance) individuals primarily engaged in performing in artistic productions, in creating artistic and cultural works or productions, or in providing technical expertise necessary for these productions. This ACPSA industry also includes athletes and other celebrities exclusively engaged in endorsing products and making speeches or public appearances for which they receive a fee.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>120</Code><Description>Museums</Description><Definition>Industries in the museums, historical sites, and similar institutions NAICS subsector engage in the preservation and exhibition of objects, sites, and natural wonders of historical, cultural, and/or educational value.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>131</Code><Description>Advertising</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in creating advertising campaigns and placing such advertising in periodicals, newspapers, radio and television, or other media. These establishments are organized to provide a full range of services (i.e., through in-house capabilities or subcontracting), including advice, creative services, account management, production of advertising material, media planning, and buying (i.e., placing advertising).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>132</Code><Description>Architectural services</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in planning and designing residential, institutional, leisure, commercial, and industrial buildings and structures by applying knowledge of design, construction procedures, zoning regulations, building codes, and building materials.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>133</Code><Description>Landscape architectural services</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in planning and designing the development of land areas for projects, such as parks and other recreational areas; airports; highways; hospitals; schools; land subdivisions; and commercial, industrial, and residential areas, by applying knowledge of land characteristics, location of buildings and structures, use of land areas, and design of landscape projects.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>134</Code><Description>Interior design services</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in planning, designing, and administering projects in interior spaces to meet the physical and aesthetic needs of people using them, taking into consideration building codes, health and safety regulations, traffic patterns and floor planning, mechanical and electrical needs, and interior fittings and furniture. Interior designers and interior design consultants work in areas, such as hospitality design, health care design, institutional design, commercial and corporate design, and residential design. This ACPSA industry also includes interior decorating consultants engaged exclusively in providing aesthetic services associated with interior spaces.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>135</Code><Description>Industrial design services</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in creating and developing designs and specifications that optimize the use, value, and appearance of their products. These services can include the determination of the materials, construction, mechanisms, shape, color, and surface finishes of the product, taking into consideration human characteristics and needs, safety, market appeal, and efficiency in production, distribution, use, and maintenance. Establishments providing automobile or furniture industrial design services or industrial design consulting services are included in this ACPSA industry.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>136</Code><Description>Graphic design services</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in planning, designing, and managing the production of visual communication in order to convey specific messages or concepts, clarify complex information, or project visual identities. These services can include the design of printed materials, packaging, advertising, signage systems, and corporate identification (logos). This ACPSA industry also includes commercial artists engaged exclusively in generating drawings and illustrations requiring technical accuracy or interpretative skills.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>137</Code><Description>Computer systems design</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in planning and designing computer systems that integrate computer hardware, software, and communication technologies. The hardware and software components of the system may be provided by this establishment or company as part of integrated services or may be provided by third parties or vendors. These establishments often install the system and train and support users of the system.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>138</Code><Description>Photography and photofinishing services</Description><Definition>These ACPSA industries comprise establishments known as portrait studios primarily engaged in providing still, video, or digital portrait photography services. Also, these industries comprise establishments primarily engaged in developing film and/or making photographic slides.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>139</Code><Description>All other design services</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in providing professional design services (except architectural, landscape architecture, engineering, interior, industrial, graphic, and computer systems design).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>140</Code><Description>Fine arts education</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in offering instruction in the arts, including dance, art, drama, and music.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>150</Code><Description>Education services</Description><Definition>The term "Educational services" is used in both the SIC and NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems.SIC definition: This SIC major group (82) includes establishments providing academic or technical instruction. Also included are establishments providing educational services such as libraries, student exchange programs, and curriculum development. Schools for the instruction of beauticians and cosmetologists are classified in Industry 7231, and barber colleges are classified in Industry 7241. Establishments primarily engaged in providing job training for the unemployed, the underemployed, the handicapped, and to persons who have a job market disadvantage because of lack of education, job skill or experience are classified in Industry 8331.NAICS definition:The Educational Services (NAICS) sector comprises establishments that provide instruction and training in a wide variety of subjects. This instruction and training is provided by specialized establishments, such as schools, colleges, universities, and training centers. These establishments may be privately owned and operated for profit or not for profit, or they may be publicly owned and operated. They may also offer food and accommodation services to their students. For the public sector, the income and employment are classified by level of government- federal, state, and local. The estimates for the federal government are sub classified into civilian and military. The different treatment of the private and public sectors means that BEA's state and local government industry includes public education, public hospitals, and other types of government services while BEA reports only private schools in its educational services industry corresponding to NAICS code 61 and only private hospitals in its hospitals industry corresponding to NAICS code 622.  Educational services (NAICS) are usually delivered by teachers or instructors that explain, tell, demonstrate, supervise, and direct learning. Instruction is imparted in diverse settings, such as educational institutions, the workplace, or the home through correspondence, television, or other means. It can be adapted to the particular needs of the students, for example sign language can replace verbal language for teaching students with hearing impairments. All industries in the sector share this commonality of process, namely, labor inputs of instructors with the requisite subject matter expertise and teaching ability.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>200</Code><Description>Supporting arts and cultural production</Description><Definition>Supporting ACPSA industries produce and disseminate arts and cultural commodities.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>211</Code><Description>Rental and leasing</Description><Definition>Industries in the rental and leasing services NAICS subsector include establishments that provide a wide array of tangible goods, such as automobiles, computers, consumer goods, and industrial machinery and equipment, to customers in return for a periodic rental or lease payment. The subsector includes two main types of establishments: (1) those that are engaged in renting consumer goods and equipment and (2) those that are engaged in leasing machinery and equipment often used for business operations. The first type typically operates from a retail-like or store-front facility and maintains inventories of goods that are rented for short periods of time. The latter type typically does not operate from retail-like locations or maintain inventories, and offers longer term leases. These establishments work directly with clients to enable them to acquire the use of equipment on a lease basis, or they work with equipment vendors or dealers to support the marketing of equipment to their customers under lease arrangements. Equipment lessors generally structure lease contracts to meet the specialized needs of their clients and use their remarketing expertise to find other users for previously leased equipment. Establishments that provide operating and capital (i.e., finance) leases are included in this subsector.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>212</Code><Description>Grantmaking and giving services</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments known as grantmaking foundations or charitable trusts. Establishments in This ACPSA industry award grants from trust funds based on a competitive selection process or the preferences of the foundation managers and grantors; or fund a single entity, such as a museum or university. In addition, these industries comprise establishments (except voluntary health organizations) primarily engaged in raising funds for a wide range of social welfare activities, such as educational, scientific, cultural, and health.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>213</Code><Description>Unions</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in promoting the interests of organized labor and union employees.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>214</Code><Description>Government</Description><Definition>Government includes the executive, legislative, judicial, administrative and regulatory activities of Federal, state, and local governments. It includes the military. Government enterprises are government agencies that cover a substantial portion of their operating costs by selling goods and services to the public and that maintain their own separate accounts.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>215</Code><Description>Other support services</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments (except travel agencies, tour operators, and convention and visitors bureaus) primarily engaged in providing travel arrangement and reservation services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>221</Code><Description>Publishing</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in carrying out all of the operations necessary for producing, distributing, and publishing newspapers, magazines and periodicals, books, greeting cards, and computer software in print and/or electronic form.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>222</Code><Description>Motion pictures</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in the production and/or distribution of motion pictures, videos, television programs, or commercials; in the exhibition of motion pictures; or in the provision of postproduction and related services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>223</Code><Description>Sound recording</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in producing and distributing musical recordings, in publishing music, or in providing sound recording and related services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>224</Code><Description>Broadcasting</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in: (1) assembling and transmitting aural programming to their affiliates or subscribers via over-the-air broadcasts, cable, or satellite; (2) television broadcasting and transmission of visual programming to affiliated broadcast television stations; (3) operating studios and facilities for the broadcasting of programs on a subscription or fee basis; (4) operation of drive-in motion picture theaters; (5) and providing specialized motion picture or video postproduction services, such as editing, film/tape transfers, subtitling, credits, closed captioning, and animation and special effects.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>225</Code><Description>Other information services</Description><Definition>Industries in the other information services NAICS subsector group establishments supplying information, storing information and providing access to information, searching and retrieving information, operating Web sites that use search engines to allow for searching information on the Internet, or publishing and/or broadcasting content exclusively on the internet. The main components of the subsector are news syndicates, libraries, archives, exclusive internet publishing and/or broadcasting, and web search portals.Under the 2007 NAICS, internet publishing and broadcasting (subsector 516) was reclassified to other information services (subsector 519).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>231</Code><Description>Jewelry and silverware manufacturing</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in one or more of the following: (1) manufacturing, engraving, chasing, or etching: jewelry, personal metal goods, metal solid, precious metal clad, hollowware; (2) stamping coins; (3) manufacturing unassembled jewelry parts and stock shop products, such as sheet, wire, and tubing; (4) cutting, slabbing, tumbling, carving, engraving, polishing, or faceting precious or semiprecious stones and gems.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>232</Code><Description>Printed goods manufacturing</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in commercial printing. Processes used in this industry include lithographic, gravure, flexographic, letterpress, engraving, and various digital printing technologies. This industry includes establishments engaged in commercial printing on purchased stock materials, such as stationery, invitations, labels, apparel and textile products, and similar items, on a job order basis. And establishments primarily engaged in traditional printing activities combined with document photocopying services or primarily engaged in printing graphical materials using digital printing equipment, printing and binding books and pamphlets without publishing, and performing prepress and postpress services in support of printing activities.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>233</Code><Description>Musical instruments manufacturing</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in manufacturing musical instruments (except toys).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>234</Code><Description>Custom architectural woodwork and metalwork manufacturing</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in: (1) manufacturing ornamental and architectural metal work; (2) manufacturing nonupholstered wood household type furniture and freestanding cabinets (except television, radio, and sewing machine cabinets), on a stock or custom basis, assembled or unassembled; (3) manufacturing custom designed interiors consisting of architectural woodwork and fixtures.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>236</Code><Description>Other goods manufacturing</Description><Definition>This U.S. industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in one or more of the following: (1) manufacturing glass by melting silica sand or cullet and making pressed, blown, or shaped glass or glassware; (2) coating, laminating, tempering, or shaping purchased glass; (3) manufacturing office supplies (pens, pencils, felt tip markers, crayons, chalk).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>240</Code><Description>Construction</Description><Definition>The term "construction" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments primarily engaged in construction. The term construction includes new work, additions, alterations, reconstruction, installations, and repairs. Construction activities are generally administered or managed from a relatively fixed place of business, but the actual construction work is performed at one or more different sites. If a company has more than one relatively fixed place of business from which it undertakes or manages construction activities and for which separate data on the number of employees, payroll, receipts, and other establishment-type records are maintained, each such place of business is considered a separate construction establishment. Three broad types of construction activity are covered: (1) building construction by general contractors or by operative builders; (2) heavy construction other than building by general contractors and special trade contractors; and (3) construction activity by other special trade contractors. NAICS definition:The construction (NAICS) sector comprises establishments primarily engaged in the construction of buildings or engineering projects (e.g., highways an utility systems). Establishments primarily engaged in the preparation of sites for new construction and establishments primarily engaged in subdividing land for sale as building sites also are included in this sector. Construction work done may include new work, additions, alterations, or maintenance and repairs. Activities of these establishments generally are managed at a fixed place of business, but they usually perform construction activities at multiple project sites. Production responsibilities in this sector are usually specified in (1) contracts with the owners of construction projects (prime contracts) or (2) contracts with other construction establishments (subcontracts).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>250</Code><Description>Wholesale and transportation industries</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in the merchant wholesale distribution of goods related to other arts industries i.e. (photographic equipment and supplies, books, periodicals, and newspapers).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>260</Code><Description>Retail industries</Description><Definition>The term "retail trade" is used in the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments engaged in selling merchandise for personal or household consumption and rendering services incidental to the sale of the goods. In general, retail establishments are classified by kind of business according to the principal lines of commodities sold (groceries, hardware, etc.), or the usual trade designation (drug store, cigar store, etc.). Some of the important characteristics of retail trade establishments are: the establishment is usually a place of business and is engaged in activities to attract the general public to buy; the establishment buys or receives merchandise as well as sells; the establishment may process its products, but such processing is incidental or subordinate to selling; the establishment is considered as retail in the trade; and the establishment sells to customers for personal or household use. Not all of these characteristics need be present and some are modified by trade practice. NAICS definition:The Retail Trade NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in retailing merchandise, generally without transformation, and rendering services incidental to the sale of merchandise. The retailing process is the final step in the distribution of merchandise; retailers are, therefore, organized to sell merchandise in small quantities to the general public. This sector comprises two main types of retailers: store and nonstore retailers. 1. Store retailers operate fixed point-of-sale locations, located and designed to attract a high volume of walk-in customers. In general, retail stores have extensive displays of merchandise and use mass-media advertising to attract customers. They typically sell merchandise to the general public for personal or household consumption, but some also serve business and institutional clients. These include establishments, such as office supply stores, computer and software stores, building materials dealers, plumbing supply stores, and electrical supply stores. Catalog showrooms, gasoline stations, automotive dealers, and mobile home dealers are treated as store retailers. In addition to retailing merchandise, some types of store retailers are also engaged in the provision of after-sales services, such as repair and installation. For example, new automobile dealers, electronic and appliance stores, and musical instrument and supply stores often provide repair services. As a general rule, establishments engaged in retailing merchandise and providing after-sales services are classified in this sector. 2. Nonstore retailers, like store retailers, are organized to serve the general public, but their retailing methods differ. The establishments of this subsector reach customers and market merchandise with methods, such as the broadcasting of "infomercials," the broadcasting and publishing of direct-response advertising, the publishing of paper and electronic catalogs, door-to-door solicitation, in-home demonstration, selling from portable stalls (street vendors, except food), and distribution through vending machines. Establishments engaged in the direct sale (nonstore) of products, such as home heating oil dealers and home delivery newspaper routes are included here.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>300</Code><Description>All other industries</Description><Definition>This ACPSA industry consists of all of the other industries not delineated above who contribute a portion to the arts and cultural production economy.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
